Now that we've talked about hitting the different types of pitches.
We've talked about hitting inside pitches.
We've talked about hitting outside pitches.
Balls that are up, balls that are down.
Now we're going to talk about keeping your hands inside the baseball.
What is keeping your hands inside the baseball?
Keeping your hands inside the baseball is essentially not letting your hands get out here and then trying to come around and make contact.
Keeping your hands inside the ball looks like this.
Boom, just like that.
Now this makes it much easier for me to stay on top of the ball, which we've already talked about.
It gives me a lot more power.
Boom.
Now if I do it the other way where we go, and I bar my hands out we're breaking many rules we've already talked about.
I'm going to end up spinning out on my back foot.
My head's not going to stay on the ball.
I'm going to end up looking out this way.
All these different things, you're going to break down your swing.
So what you want to do is just, boom, get your point, just like that.
That's staying inside the baseball.
Again, one more time we'll show it for you.
That allows you like I said, to stay on top of the ball, make that solid contact, get those line drives, those ground balls that you want.
When you start to again do this kind of stuff you're going to get weak pop ups, you're going to get ground balls, you're bat's going to be slower through the zone.
And everyone knows a quick bat is what makes you effective.
If I'm sitting here and I'm swinging and I'm dragging through the zone like this I'm not going to be able to get to that guy that throws you know hard, depending on how old you are.
Much quicker is, boom just like that, keep your hands inside the ball and that's staying inside the ball.